<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </title>
    <link>cjap/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="cjap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inclusivity in Psychology at Concordia University</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/edi-editorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/edi-editorial/</guid>
      <description>Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (EDI) have gained significant spotlight in academic circles over the past 10 years, highlighting how important they are. EDI is an umbrella term of all the approaches that aim to ensure equitable representation and inclusion of diverse views in scientific research and clinical practice. Its overarching goal is to produce science that is more equitable, representative, and, ultimately, more valid in benefiting all groups of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE BODY POSITIVITY MOVEMENT; WHAT IS AND WHAT COULD BE?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/body-positivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/body-positivity/</guid>
      <description>I am ugly. I don’t like what I see in the mirror. I need to stop eating and start exercising. I will never be attractive. Why can’t I be like them? This is so unfair. 
Have you experienced similar thoughts? These thoughts and their associated feelings contribute to negative body image, or in other words, perceptions of one’s body. Body image is influenced by beauty standards, as social norms define what the ideal appearance is (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Should You Be Doing at Night?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/night-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/night-sleep/</guid>
      <description>In our fast-paced world, where to-do lists seem never-ending, deadlines are tight, and nightlife is bustling, it can be challenging to prioritize our health and well-being. Even more so, the prevalent and highly regarded &amp;ldquo;go-go-go&amp;rdquo; lifestyle creates a constant state of urgency that makes prioritizing our health and well-being even more difficult. Unfortunately, the most important aspect of our well-being is often the one that gets neglected the most: sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARE YOU MICONCEIVING MINORITY PEOPLE&#39;S IDENTITIES; A GATEWAY INTO WHITEWASHING?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/perception-of-minorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/perception-of-minorities/</guid>
      <description>If you live in Canada, you know it is an ethnically diverse country, but have you ever thought about how you assume a person’s ethnic origin? Canada is home to over 400,000 immigrants, a number that continues to rise, and Middle Eastern refugees currently account for 11% of these immigrants [1,2]. The ability to perceive minority groups affects the authenticity of our interactions and relationships with individuals from these groups [3].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COLOUR BLINDNESS; PERCEIVING THE WORLD THROUGH A DIFFERENT LENS</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/colour-blindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/colour-blindness/</guid>
      <description>The ability to perceive colour is something people usually take for granted. It is not something you are taught in school or that can be learned, but something you are born with. In fact, from the moment you wake up until you go to sleep, colours are essential to help us navigate throughout our daily lives. The majority of people have a similar colour perception, however, 7% of males and 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>METHOD OR MADNESS? EXPLORING THE PSYCHOLOGICAL EFFECTS OF METHOD ACTING</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/method-or-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/method-or-madness/</guid>
      <description>From Nicolas Cage having his teeth pulled out without anesthesia for the film Birdy to Leonardo DiCaprio, an avid vegetarian, sleeping in animal carcasses in The Revenant, many actors are devoted followers of “method acting,” a technique which requires performers to fully inhabit the identity of a fictional character, rather than simply memorizing and reciting lines [1, 2]. Such actors are often met with critical acclaim and celebrated with awards for their efforts, as they completely transform their bodies and perform dangerous stunts to fully immerse themselves in their performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety and Weed; A Way to Relax or a Recipe for Disaster?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/anxiety-weed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/anxiety-weed/</guid>
      <description>“Here, smoke this, it’ll help you unwind.”
Some cannabis users swear by its ability to help them manage their anxiety and better socialize, others won’t touch the stuff, worried it will only serve to increase their stress and paranoia. Love it or hate it, “weed” has been used for centuries for both medicinal and recreational purposes, and a lot of people are consuming it. There were more than 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are the Japanese Macaques at Granby Zoo, Québec Good at Hair Massages?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/japanese-macaques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/japanese-macaques/</guid>
      <description>Humans are not the only primate species that enjoys a nice hair massage from their partner! Many non-human primates enjoy it just as much as we do. Grooming is defined as someone’s fur being tended to by another individual and plays an important role in a Japanese Macaque’s daily life since it has a social and hygienic function.
For social interactions, grooming is used to co-exist and reduce tensions among primates which is potentially caused by the competition for access to females [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Jealous in your Relationship? Your Anxious Attachment Style may be to Blame</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/jealous-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/jealous-relationships/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that you are out on a typical dinner date and your significant other is ‘talking’ way too much with the waiter which makes you feel insecure, fearful or concerned about your relationship: that’s jealousy. Most of us have experienced jealousy as a reaction to romantic relationships at some point in our life. Did you know that this feeling can stem from having an anxious attachment style? Jealousy is especially prevalent when we are involved in a romantic relationship as it motivates one to take action to protect the relationship [3,4].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Takes Two; What Can We Learn From Identical Twins?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/identical-twins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/identical-twins/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered about the causes of mental illness and negative life outcomes? While we know that both nature (genetics) and nurture (the environment) play an important role, the specifics are still unclear. For scientists, identical twins offer a unique way to investigate the impact of the environment on mental health and development [1]. Identical twins have long been studied in the medical field to explore the causes of disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living Life Like it’s a Marathon; How Grit Helps You Overcome Challenges</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/life-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/life-marathon/</guid>
      <description>During challenging and uncertain times such as the COVID-19 pandemic, many of the goals we previously set are no longer attainable, either temporarily or indefinitely, which has a negative impact on our well-being [1]. For many, educational goals have been impacted due to struggles with online learning, relationship goals due to social distancing restrictions, and career/financial goals due to loss of work, reduced hours, or reduced opportunities. Notably, one survey showed that 71% of college students reported that their stress and anxiety levels had increased during the pandemic because they were worried about not being able to meet their goals, be it academic, work, or financial [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Older Adults Walking to Rhythmic Auditory Cues</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/older-adult-walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/older-adult-walking/</guid>
      <description>Have you witnessed the rehabilitation from a falling episode from friends or family members? In fact, about 81% of injury-related hospitalization cases for Canadian seniors are due to falls, and elderly adults rarely fully recover [1]. While walking seems automatic, the walking speed and the timing of footsteps are markers that can predict older adults’ physical and cognitive functioning. Therefore, interventions that help elderly adults achieve a more regular and stable walking pattern would have benefits for the individual’s physical health status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting your best foot forward; Understanding fall risk among Older Adults</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/odler-adult-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/odler-adult-fall/</guid>
      <description>Your 83-year-old grandmother is walking on uneven ground past a park. Instead of stopping to observe the park, she continues walking while her attention is drawn to the children playing on a swing set. Your grandmother, who has significant visual and hearing impairments, suddenly finds herself losing her balance and falling to the ground. Imagine yourself in that same situation, would you have fallen? Most likely, you would have carried out the two tasks (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Relations, Trauma Research and Compassionate Activism</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/race-relations-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/race-relations-trauma/</guid>
      <description>There are few wounds that cut as deep as racial oppression. Compassionate activism may allow us to fight for change while consciously considering these wounds of the past. In our contentious debates about race relations, we have failed to pay adequate attention to what the last 25 years of research tells us about how racial discrimination can be addressed. Processing present day racial oppression through the lens of trauma psychology allows us to see that compassionate activism can address the trauma of the past while fighting the injustice of the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save a seat for seniors!</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/seat-seniors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/seat-seniors/</guid>
      <description>We’ve all been there. You are standing on a bus, all the seats are taken, so you hold on for dear life. At the next stop, an older adult boards the bus, and sadly no one is willing to give up their seat for them. You start giving the sitters some passive-aggressive stares in the hopes that they catch on and step up (quite literally) to the occasion. But why is it so important for them to sacrifice their pleasurable sitting experience for the older individual?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emotional Chaos Behind Disordered Eating</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/disordered-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/disordered-eating/</guid>
      <description>It’s the end of a stressful day at work and you’re about to head out when you get into a fight with a colleague. Then, a careless driver cuts you off on your way home and almost causes a crash. Needless to say, you’re upset. You get home, and suddenly, that chocolate cake waiting in the fridge is the only thing on your mind. You open the fridge, take one bite, and before you know it, the whole thing is gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adult Picky Eating; A Distinct Category of Disordered Eating?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/picky-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/picky-eating/</guid>
      <description>Eating disorders are distressing and serious psychiatric illnesses involving disordered eating patterns and/or unhealthy strategies to control weight [1]. In past decades, prevalence rates of eating disorders have globally increased by 25%. These serious disorders can lead to many physical and psychological problems for the individual (e.g., malnutrition, low self-esteem) and, in some cases, death [1]. Additionally, the development of eating disorders involves an interaction between biological (e.g., genes), psychological (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIGHWAYS OF THE BRAIN; THE UNDEREXAMINED COMPONENT THAT BRINGS EVERYTHING TOGETHER</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/highways-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/highways-brain/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered whether different locations of the brain talk to each other? They do, in fact, constantly communicate with each other. This communication is somewhat like how we as individuals communicate with those around us. For example, we send and receive information every day, such as when we wave hello to a friend (send) and they wave back at us (receive). Similarly, different regions of the brain send and receive information between each other to help perceive and interpret the world we live in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IN SEARCH OF HOW BRAIN CONNECTIONS CREATE THE MIND</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/brain-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/brain-connections/</guid>
      <description>Imagine sitting at a table on the terrace of a café in Paris. It’s nighttime, but the boulevard’s lampposts’ glow and the café’s signage light up the dark sky. The usual crowds are thinning, and several smartly dressed couples pass by with their cigarette smoke wafting in their wake. Lifting your cup of aromatic coffee to your lips, you find yourself captivated by the conversations taking place around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IS THE MEMORY FOR YOUR FAVORITE BRANDS DEEPLY ROOTED IN YOUR SUBCONSCIOUS PROCESSES?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/memory-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/memory-brands/</guid>
      <description>Our globalized market has an abundance of brands that we, consumers can choose from. Not only do we get bombarded with a variety of brands in our local grocery store, but we also see even more when travelling and through social media. Consequently, these factors can affect our prior experience and exposure on which brands we become familiar with[1]. Are our brand choices and decisions in the local grocery store voluntary or are we simply subject to subconscious processes in the brain?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LET’S NOT TRIP OUT JUST YET!</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/lets-not-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/lets-not-trip/</guid>
      <description>Don your flower crowns and turn up the Hendrix - psychedelics are back! Through legally conducted research with these illegal substances, scientists have found that psilocybin, the ingredient in hallucinogenic mushrooms that makes people feel “groovy”, is associated with improvements in people’s mental health. The varied effects of psilocybin such as intense introspective insights, visual hallucinations, and euphoria give credence to the etymology of the term psychedelic (psyche for mind and delos for manifesting in Greek).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAKE A PAWS; HOW ANIMALS LEARN TO INHIBIT RESPONSES</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/animal-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/animal-learning/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is filled with animal videos like a cat scurrying into the kitchen after hearing a bag of treats shake or a dog doing a bizarre trick to get some food. Besides these videos being quite entertaining, they also demonstrate how animals can gain an understanding of their environment. Due to this fundamental ability to learn, animals can produce these remarkable—and, of course, cute—responses. Animals learn to respond by forming associations in the environment, either between stimuli or a response and its consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE DEATH OF YOUR BEST FRIENDS</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/death-best-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/death-best-friend/</guid>
      <description>This is an image I took of a mouse neuron while working on my thesis. I’ve always liked to call neurons our best friends because they care for us, provide us support, and without them, we would struggle to accomplish tasks and goals we set for ourselves. However, just like real friends, a healthy relationship must be maintained. The loss of a friend, also known as neuronal death, can arise through a variety of ways from brain damage, substance abuse to old age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRUSTING YOUR BODY’S INTERNAL CLOCK; IS IT LUNCHTIME YET?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/internal-clock-lunchtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/internal-clock-lunchtime/</guid>
      <description>As humans, we are hardwired to seek out situations that meet our biological needs. We attribute the most time and energy to circumstances that simultaneously provide physiological and psychological satisfaction. Among these circumstances are opportunities to eat. On a daily basis, we invest a great deal of monetary resources into food, and we take pleasure in fantasizing about our next great feast. These primal instincts are under the control one of the body’s most important systems: circadian rhythms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHAT ARE CIRCADIAN CLOCKS AND HOW CAN THEY HELP UNDERSTAND PSYCHIATRIC DISORDERS?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/circadian-clock-psychiatry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/circadian-clock-psychiatry/</guid>
      <description>Picture yourself in a room stripped of windows and light sources with no alarm clocks, cell phones, or television. Under complete darkness and in the absence of external cues, how would you be able to tell time? How would you know when to sleep or wake-up? Would it affect your mood? It turns out, your body would maintain rhythms of behavior and physiological processes that last around 24-hours, because of your internal circadian clocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“LET’S TALK ABOUT THIS… ONCE MORE!”; REPETITIVE NEGATIVE TALK WITH FRIENDS</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/ruminate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/ruminate/</guid>
      <description>People regularly turn conversations into co-rumination: discussing the same problems, over and over again, in a very negative way. A classic example involves friends who obsessively talk about their ex-lovers. They might spend a lot of time and effort mentally going back over every little detail to try and understand the breakups. They may pine over and even criticize the ex-partners. Co-ruminating about exes is typical, but there are also infinite examples of excessive negative problem sharing in the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 1</title>
      <link>cjap/itemized/item1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/itemized/item1/</guid>
      <description>App 1 text after image
Haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to get html to work for images</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 2</title>
      <link>cjap/itemized/item2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/itemized/item2/</guid>
      <description>App 2 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 3</title>
      <link>cjap/itemized/item3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/itemized/item3/</guid>
      <description>App 3 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 4</title>
      <link>cjap/itemized/item4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/itemized/item4/</guid>
      <description>App 4 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact the CJAP Team</title>
      <link>cjap/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow us on Social Media! Follow us on Twitter.
Check out our Facebook page
 Email us and we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you at lightning speed Click here to email CJAP</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
