<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </title>
    <link>/cjap/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/cjap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adult Picky Eating; A Distinct Category of Disordered Eating?</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/picky-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/picky-eating/</guid>
      <description>Eating disorders are distressing and serious psychiatric illnesses involving disordered eating patterns and/or unhealthy strategies to control weight [1]. In past decades, prevalence rates of eating disorders have globally increased by 25%. These serious disorders can lead to many physical and psychological problems for the individual (e.g., malnutrition, low self-esteem) and, in some cases, death [1]. Additionally, the development of eating disorders involves an interaction between biological (e.g., genes), psychological (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIGHWAYS OF THE BRAIN; THE UNDEREXAMINED COMPONENT THAT BRINGS EVERYTHING TOGETHER</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/highways-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/highways-brain/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered whether different locations of the brain talk to each other? They do, in fact, constantly communicate with each other. This communication is somewhat like how we as individuals communicate with those around us. For example, we send and receive information every day, such as when we wave hello to a friend (send) and they wave back at us (receive). Similarly, different regions of the brain send and receive information between each other to help perceive and interpret the world we live in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IN SEARCH OF HOW BRAIN CONNECTIONS CREATE THE MIND</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/brain-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/brain-connections/</guid>
      <description>Imagine sitting at a table on the terrace of a café in Paris. It’s nighttime, but the boulevard’s lampposts’ glow and the café’s signage light up the dark sky. The usual crowds are thinning, and several smartly dressed couples pass by with their cigarette smoke wafting in their wake. Lifting your cup of aromatic coffee to your lips, you find yourself captivated by the conversations taking place around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IS THE MEMORY FOR YOUR FAVORITE BRANDS DEEPLY ROOTED IN YOUR SUBCONSCIOUS PROCESSES?</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/memory-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/memory-brands/</guid>
      <description>Our globalized market has an abundance of brands that we, consumers can choose from. Not only do we get bombarded with a variety of brands in our local grocery store, but we also see even more when travelling and through social media. Consequently, these factors can affect our prior experience and exposure on which brands we become familiar with[1]. Are our brand choices and decisions in the local grocery store voluntary or are we simply subject to subconscious processes in the brain?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LET’S NOT TRIP OUT JUST YET!</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/lets-not-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/lets-not-trip/</guid>
      <description>Don your flower crowns and turn up the Hendrix - psychedelics are back! Through legally conducted research with these illegal substances, scientists have found that psilocybin, the ingredient in hallucinogenic mushrooms that makes people feel “groovy”, is associated with improvements in people’s mental health. The varied effects of psilocybin such as intense introspective insights, visual hallucinations, and euphoria give credence to the etymology of the term psychedelic (psyche for mind and delos for manifesting in Greek).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAKE A PAWS; HOW ANIMALS LEARN TO INHIBIT RESPONSES</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/animal-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/animal-learning/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is filled with animal videos like a cat scurrying into the kitchen after hearing a bag of treats shake or a dog doing a bizarre trick to get some food. Besides these videos being quite entertaining, they also demonstrate how animals can gain an understanding of their environment. Due to this fundamental ability to learn, animals can produce these remarkable—and, of course, cute—responses. Animals learn to respond by forming associations in the environment, either between stimuli or a response and its consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE DEATH OF YOUR BEST FRIENDS</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/death-best-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/death-best-friend/</guid>
      <description>This is an image I took of a mouse neuron while working on my thesis. I’ve always liked to call neurons our best friends because they care for us, provide us support, and without them, we would struggle to accomplish tasks and goals we set for ourselves. However, just like real friends, a healthy relationship must be maintained. The loss of a friend, also known as neuronal death, can arise through a variety of ways from brain damage, substance abuse to old age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TRUSTING YOUR BODY’S INTERNAL CLOCK; IS IT LUNCHTIME YET?</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/internal-clock-lunchtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/internal-clock-lunchtime/</guid>
      <description>As humans, we are hardwired to seek out situations that meet our biological needs. We attribute the most time and energy to circumstances that simultaneously provide physiological and psychological satisfaction. Among these circumstances are opportunities to eat. On a daily basis, we invest a great deal of monetary resources into food, and we take pleasure in fantasizing about our next great feast. These primal instincts are under the control one of the body’s most important systems: circadian rhythms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHAT ARE CIRCADIAN CLOCKS AND HOW CAN THEY HELP UNDERSTAND PSYCHIATRIC DISORDERS?</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/circadian-clock-psychiatry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/circadian-clock-psychiatry/</guid>
      <description>Picture yourself in a room stripped of windows and light sources with no alarm clocks, cell phones, or television. Under complete darkness and in the absence of external cues, how would you be able to tell time? How would you know when to sleep or wake-up? Would it affect your mood? It turns out, your body would maintain rhythms of behavior and physiological processes that last around 24-hours, because of your internal circadian clocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“LET’S TALK ABOUT THIS… ONCE MORE!”; REPETITIVE NEGATIVE TALK WITH FRIENDS</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/ruminate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/ruminate/</guid>
      <description>People regularly turn conversations into co-rumination: discussing the same problems, over and over again, in a very negative way. A classic example involves friends who obsessively talk about their ex-lovers. They might spend a lot of time and effort mentally going back over every little detail to try and understand the breakups. They may pine over and even criticize the ex-partners. Co-ruminating about exes is typical, but there are also infinite examples of excessive negative problem sharing in the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 1</title>
      <link>/cjap/itemized/item1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/itemized/item1/</guid>
      <description>App 1 text after image
Haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to get html to work for images</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 2</title>
      <link>/cjap/itemized/item2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/itemized/item2/</guid>
      <description>App 2 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 3</title>
      <link>/cjap/itemized/item3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/itemized/item3/</guid>
      <description>App 3 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy App 4</title>
      <link>/cjap/itemized/item4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/itemized/item4/</guid>
      <description>App 4 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact the CJAP Team</title>
      <link>/cjap/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow us on Social Media! Follow us on Twitter.
Check out our Facebook page
 Email us and we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you at lightning speed Click here to email CJAP</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
