<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eye-tracking on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </title>
    <link>cjap/categories/eye-tracking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eye-tracking on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="cjap/categories/eye-tracking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Race Relations, Trauma Research and Compassionate Activism</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/race-relations-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/race-relations-trauma/</guid>
      <description>There are few wounds that cut as deep as racial oppression. Compassionate activism may allow us to fight for change while consciously considering these wounds of the past. In our contentious debates about race relations, we have failed to pay adequate attention to what the last 25 years of research tells us about how racial discrimination can be addressed. Processing present day racial oppression through the lens of trauma psychology allows us to see that compassionate activism can address the trauma of the past while fighting the injustice of the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IS THE MEMORY FOR YOUR FAVORITE BRANDS DEEPLY ROOTED IN YOUR SUBCONSCIOUS PROCESSES?</title>
      <link>cjap/blog/memory-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>cjap/blog/memory-brands/</guid>
      <description>Our globalized market has an abundance of brands that we, consumers can choose from. Not only do we get bombarded with a variety of brands in our local grocery store, but we also see even more when travelling and through social media. Consequently, these factors can affect our prior experience and exposure on which brands we become familiar with[1]. Are our brand choices and decisions in the local grocery store voluntary or are we simply subject to subconscious processes in the brain?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
