<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cognitive psychology on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </title>
    <link>/cjap/categories/cognitive-psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cognitive psychology on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/cjap/categories/cognitive-psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ARE YOU MICONCEIVING MINORITY PEOPLE&#39;S IDENTITIES; A GATEWAY INTO WHITEWASHING?</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/perception-of-minorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/perception-of-minorities/</guid>
      <description>If you live in Canada, you know it is an ethnically diverse country, but have you ever thought about how you assume a person’s ethnic origin? Canada is home to over 400,000 immigrants, a number that continues to rise, and Middle Eastern refugees currently account for 11% of these immigrants [1,2]. The ability to perceive minority groups affects the authenticity of our interactions and relationships with individuals from these groups [3].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COLOUR BLINDNESS; PERCEIVING THE WORLD THROUGH A DIFFERENT LENS</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/colour-blindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/colour-blindness/</guid>
      <description>The ability to perceive colour is something people usually take for granted. It is not something you are taught in school or that can be learned, but something you are born with. In fact, from the moment you wake up until you go to sleep, colours are essential to help us navigate throughout our daily lives. The majority of people have a similar colour perception, however, 7% of males and 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
