<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aging on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </title>
    <link>/cjap/categories/aging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aging on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/cjap/categories/aging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Older Adults Walking to Rhythmic Auditory Cues</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/older-adult-walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/older-adult-walking/</guid>
      <description>Have you witnessed the rehabilitation from a falling episode from friends or family members? In fact, about 81% of injury-related hospitalization cases for Canadian seniors are due to falls, and elderly adults rarely fully recover [1]. While walking seems automatic, the walking speed and the timing of footsteps are markers that can predict older adults’ physical and cognitive functioning. Therefore, interventions that help elderly adults achieve a more regular and stable walking pattern would have benefits for the individual’s physical health status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting your best foot forward; Understanding fall risk among Older Adults</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/odler-adult-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/odler-adult-fall/</guid>
      <description>Your 83-year-old grandmother is walking on uneven ground past a park. Instead of stopping to observe the park, she continues walking while her attention is drawn to the children playing on a swing set. Your grandmother, who has significant visual and hearing impairments, suddenly finds herself losing her balance and falling to the ground. Imagine yourself in that same situation, would you have fallen? Most likely, you would have carried out the two tasks (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE DEATH OF YOUR BEST FRIENDS</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/death-best-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/death-best-friend/</guid>
      <description>This is an image I took of a mouse neuron while working on my thesis. I’ve always liked to call neurons our best friends because they care for us, provide us support, and without them, we would struggle to accomplish tasks and goals we set for ourselves. However, just like real friends, a healthy relationship must be maintained. The loss of a friend, also known as neuronal death, can arise through a variety of ways from brain damage, substance abuse to old age.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
