<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Disorders on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </title>
    <link>/cjap/categories/disorders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Disorders on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/cjap/categories/disorders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Jealous in your Relationship? Your Anxious Attachment Style may be to Blame</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/jealous-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/jealous-relationships/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that you are out on a typical dinner date and your significant other is ‘talking’ way too much with the waiter which makes you feel insecure, fearful or concerned about your relationship: that’s jealousy. Most of us have experienced jealousy as a reaction to romantic relationships at some point in our life. Did you know that this feeling can stem from having an anxious attachment style? Jealousy is especially prevalent when we are involved in a romantic relationship as it motivates one to take action to protect the relationship [3,4].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save a seat for seniors!</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/seat-seniors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/seat-seniors/</guid>
      <description>We’ve all been there. You are standing on a bus, all the seats are taken, so you hold on for dear life. At the next stop, an older adult boards the bus, and sadly no one is willing to give up their seat for them. You start giving the sitters some passive-aggressive stares in the hopes that they catch on and step up (quite literally) to the occasion. But why is it so important for them to sacrifice their pleasurable sitting experience for the older individual?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emotional Chaos Behind Disordered Eating</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/disordered-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/disordered-eating/</guid>
      <description>It’s the end of a stressful day at work and you’re about to head out when you get into a fight with a colleague. Then, a careless driver cuts you off on your way home and almost causes a crash. Needless to say, you’re upset. You get home, and suddenly, that chocolate cake waiting in the fridge is the only thing on your mind. You open the fridge, take one bite, and before you know it, the whole thing is gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adult Picky Eating; A Distinct Category of Disordered Eating?</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/picky-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/picky-eating/</guid>
      <description>Eating disorders are distressing and serious psychiatric illnesses involving disordered eating patterns and/or unhealthy strategies to control weight [1]. In past decades, prevalence rates of eating disorders have globally increased by 25%. These serious disorders can lead to many physical and psychological problems for the individual (e.g., malnutrition, low self-esteem) and, in some cases, death [1]. Additionally, the development of eating disorders involves an interaction between biological (e.g., genes), psychological (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“LET’S TALK ABOUT THIS… ONCE MORE!”; REPETITIVE NEGATIVE TALK WITH FRIENDS</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/ruminate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/ruminate/</guid>
      <description>People regularly turn conversations into co-rumination: discussing the same problems, over and over again, in a very negative way. A classic example involves friends who obsessively talk about their ex-lovers. They might spend a lot of time and effort mentally going back over every little detail to try and understand the breakups. They may pine over and even criticize the ex-partners. Co-ruminating about exes is typical, but there are also infinite examples of excessive negative problem sharing in the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
