<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Disorders on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </title>
    <link>/cjap/categories/disorders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Disorders on CJAP | Concordia Journal of Accessible Psychology </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/cjap/categories/disorders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adult Picky Eating; A Distinct Category of Disordered Eating?</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/picky-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/picky-eating/</guid>
      <description>Eating disorders are distressing and serious psychiatric illnesses involving disordered eating patterns and/or unhealthy strategies to control weight [1]. In past decades, prevalence rates of eating disorders have globally increased by 25%. These serious disorders can lead to many physical and psychological problems for the individual (e.g., malnutrition, low self-esteem) and, in some cases, death [1]. Additionally, the development of eating disorders involves an interaction between biological (e.g., genes), psychological (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“LET’S TALK ABOUT THIS… ONCE MORE!”; REPETITIVE NEGATIVE TALK WITH FRIENDS</title>
      <link>/cjap/blog/ruminate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cjap/blog/ruminate/</guid>
      <description>People regularly turn conversations into co-rumination: discussing the same problems, over and over again, in a very negative way. A classic example involves friends who obsessively talk about their ex-lovers. They might spend a lot of time and effort mentally going back over every little detail to try and understand the breakups. They may pine over and even criticize the ex-partners. Co-ruminating about exes is typical, but there are also infinite examples of excessive negative problem sharing in the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
