<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CJAP 2019-2020 on Hugo Future Imperfect</title>
    <link>/home/tags/cjap-2019-2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CJAP 2019-2020 on Hugo Future Imperfect</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/home/tags/cjap-2019-2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adult Picky Eating; A Distinct Category of Disordered Eating?</title>
      <link>/home/blog/picky-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/blog/picky-eating/</guid>
      <description>Eating disorders are distressing and serious psychiatric illnesses involving disordered eating patterns and/or unhealthy strategies to control weight [1]. In past decades, prevalence rates of eating disorders have globally increased by 25%. These serious disorders can lead to many physical and psychological problems for the individual (e.g., malnutrition, low self-esteem) and, in some cases, death [1]. Additionally, the development of eating disorders involves an interaction between biological (e.g., genes), psychological (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LET’S NOT TRIP OUT JUST YET!</title>
      <link>/home/blog/lets-not-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/blog/lets-not-trip/</guid>
      <description>Don your flower crowns and turn up the Hendrix - psychedelics are back! Through legally conducted research with these illegal substances, scientists have found that psilocybin, the ingredient in hallucinogenic mushrooms that makes people feel “groovy”, is associated with improvements in people’s mental health. The varied effects of psilocybin such as intense introspective insights, visual hallucinations, and euphoria give credence to the etymology of the term psychedelic (psyche for mind and delos for manifesting in Greek).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE DEATH OF YOUR BEST FRIENDS</title>
      <link>/home/blog/death-best-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/blog/death-best-friend/</guid>
      <description>This is an image I took of a mouse neuron while working on my thesis. I’ve always liked to call neurons our best friends because they care for us, provide us support, and without them, we would struggle to accomplish tasks and goals we set for ourselves. However, just like real friends, a healthy relationship must be maintained. The loss of a friend, also known as neuronal death, can arise through a variety of ways from brain damage, substance abuse to old age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“LET’S TALK ABOUT THIS… ONCE MORE!”; REPETITIVE NEGATIVE TALK WITH FRIENDS</title>
      <link>/home/blog/ruminate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/blog/ruminate/</guid>
      <description>People regularly turn conversations into co-rumination: discussing the same problems, over and over again, in a very negative way. A classic example involves friends who obsessively talk about their ex-lovers. They might spend a lot of time and effort mentally going back over every little detail to try and understand the breakups. They may pine over and even criticize the ex-partners. Co-ruminating about exes is typical, but there are also infinite examples of excessive negative problem sharing in the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
